Lucas Daniel Lo Vercio, Ph.D.

POSTDOCTORAL ASSOCIATE

Department of Cell Biology & Anatomy, University of Calgary, HRIC 3A29, 3300 Hospital Drive, Calgary, AB, Canada

□ +1 403-923-9735 | ■ lucasdaniel.lovercio@ucalgary.ca | ♠ https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Lucas_Lo_Vercio | □ https://github.com/lucaslovercio/ | □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-lo-vercio/

Summary _____

Born in Quilmes, Argentina, on May 12, 1987. I am a computer scientist with a strong background in mathematics. My research fields are medical and biological images analysis and machine learning. Currently, I am researching on automatic segmentation, registration and quantification of fluorescence microscopy images using deep learning, for supporting developmental biology research. Previously, I worked on the automatic analysis of a variety of ultrasound images (IVUS, carotid ultrasound) for clinical research, diagnosis and training. Furthermore, I am highly experienced in university-level teaching and mentoring.

Education _____

Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires (UNCPBA)

Tandil, Argentina 2012-2017

PHD IN COMPUTATIONAL AND INDUSTRIAL MATHEMATICS.

- Thesis Title: Feature engineering and machine learning for intravascular ultrasound segmentation.
- Supervisors: Dr. Ignacio Larrabide and Dr. Mariana del Fresno (PLADEMA Research Institute).

UNCPBA Tandil, Argentina
Systems Engineer 2005-2011

- Final project title: Multiresolution visulization of topographic meshes.
- Supervisors: Dr. Alejandro Clausse and Msc. Virginia Cifuentes (PLADEMA Research Institute).

UNCPBA Tandil, Argentina
COMPUTER PROGRAMMER ANALYST 2005 - 2010

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

- 2018 Argentina National Space Activities Commission (CONAE), Level 2: Introduction to SAR remote sensing
- 2017 CONAE, Introduction to Geospatial Technologies in Agriculture
- 2016 CONAE, SoPI I: Introduction to Remote Sensing

Current and Past Positions _____

2018-date	Postdoctoral associate, Eyes High Postdoctoral Fellow (2018-2020) , Department of Cell Biology & Anatomy, University of Calgary, Canada. Supervisors: Dr. Benedikt Hallgrímsson and Dr. Nils Forkert.
2017-2018	Postdoctoral Fellow , National Scientific and Technical Research Council (CONICET), PLADEMA-UNCPBA.
	Argentina
2012-2017	PhD Fellow, National Scientific and Technical Research Council (CONICET), PLADEMA-UNCPBA. Argentina
2012-2019	Graduate Teaching Assistant, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas, UNCPBA, Argentina
2011-2012	Software Developer, UNITECH S.A., Buenos Aires, Argentina
2009-2012	Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas, UNCPBA, Argentina

_		٠.	. •	
Pι	ıh	lica	1†1 <i>C</i>	าทร

PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES

- **Lucas D. Lo Vercio**, Rebecca M. Green, Samuel Robertson, Sienna Guo, Andreas Dauter, Marta Marchini, Marta Vidal-García, Xiang Zhao, Anandita Mahika, Ralph S. Marcucio, Benedikt Hallgrímsson, Nils D. Forkert. *Segmentation of Tissues and Proliferating Cells in Light-Sheet Microscopy Images of Mouse Embryos Using Convolutional Neural Networks.* IEEE Access. 2022; 11, 105084-105100.
- Jay Devine, Marta Vidal-García, Wei Liu, Amanda Neves, **Lucas D. Lo Vercio**, Rebecca M. Green, Heather A. Richbourg, Marta Marchini, et al. *MusMorph, a database of standardized mouse morphology data for morphometric meta-analyses.* Scientific Data. 2022.
- Nicolas Toussaint, Yushi Redhead, Marta Vidal-García, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Wei Liu, Elizabeth M. C. Fisher, Benedikt Hallgrímsson, Victor L. J. Tybulewicz, Julia A. Schnabel, Jeremy B. A. Green. *A landmark-free morphometrics pipeline for high-resolution phenotyping: application to a mouse model of Down syndrome*. Development. 2021; 148 (18).
- Marta Marchini, Diane Hu, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Nathan M. Young, Nils D. Forkert, Benedikt Hallgrímsson, Ralph Marcucio. *Wnt Signaling Drives Correlated Changes in Facial Morphology and Brain Shape*. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology. 2021.
- Jay Devine, Jose D. Aponte, David C. Katz, Wei Liu, **Lucas D. Lo Vercio**, Nils D. Forkert, Ralph Marcucio, Christopher J. Percival, Benedikt Hallgrímsson. *A Registration and Deep Learning Approach to Automated Landmark Detection for Geometric Morphometrics*. Evolutionary Biology. 2020; 47, 246–259.
- **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Mariana del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Lumen-intima and media-adventitia segmentation in IVUS images using supervised classifications of arterial layers and morphological structures.* Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine. 2019. 177, 113-121.
- Hugo Luis Manterola, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Alejandro Díaz, Mariana del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Validation of an Open-Source Tool for Measuring Carotid Lumen Diameter and Intima–Media Thickness*. Ultrasound in Medicine & Biology. 2018. 44 (8), 1873-1881.
- Alejandro Diaz, Daniel Bia, Yanina Zócalo, Hugo Manterola, Ignacio Larrabide, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Mariana Del Fresno, Edmundo Cabrera Fischer. *Carotid Intima Media Thickness Reference Intervals for a Healthy Argentinean Population Aged 11–81 Years*. International Journal of Hypertension. 2018.
- **Lucas Lo Vercio**, José Ignacio Orlando, Mariana del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Assessment of image features for vessel wall segmentation in intravascular ultrasound images*. International Journal of Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery. 2016. 11, 1397–1407.

TUTORIALS AND LITERATURE REVIEWS

Lucas Lo Vercio, Kimberly Amador, Jordan J. Bannister, Sebastian Crites, Alejandro Gutierrez, M. Ethan MacDonald, Jasmine Moore, Pauline Mouches, Deepthi Rajashekar, Serena Schimert, Nagesh Subbanna, Anup Tuladhar, Nanjia Wang, Matthias Wilms, Anthony Winder, Nils D. Forkert. *Supervised machine learning tools: a tutorial for clinicians.* Journal of Neural Engineering. 2020; 17 (6).

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE PAPERS

- **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Mariana Del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Detection of morphological structures for vessel wall segmentation in IVUS using random forests*. Proc. SPIE 10160, 12th International Symposium on Medical Information Processing and Analysis. 2017.
- Hugo Luis Manterola, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Alejandro Díaz, Pamela Alejandra Pardini, María Victoria Waks Serra, Mariana del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Low-cost phantoms for validating measurements in ultrasound vascular images.* Proc. SPIE 10160, 12th International Symposium on Medical Information Processing and Analysis. 2017.
- Juan P. D'Amato, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Pablo Rubi, Ezequiel Fernandez Vera, Rosana Barbuzza, Mariana Del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Efficient scatter model for simulation of ultrasound images from computed tomography data*. Proc. SPIE 9681, 11th International Symposium on Medical Information Processing and Analysis. 2015.
- **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Javier Dottori, Ignacio Larrabide, Jose Luis Díez-Gil, Mariana del Fresno, Pablo Lotito. *Guidewire artifact tracking on IVUS*. V MACI. Tandil, Buenos Aires, Argentina. 2015.
- Hugo Manterola, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Mariana del Fresno. *Reducing Artifacts Impact on IVUS Automatic Segmentation Via Inpainting*. Mecánica Computacional. 2014. 33 (41).

Presentations_

CONFERENCE TALKS

Conference Papers mentioned before were presented, but omitted here. * presenting author; * mentored undergraduate

- **Lucas Lo Vercio***, Rebecca Green, Andreas Dauter, Elizabeth Barretto, Marta Marchini, Marta Vidal-García, Samuel Robertson, Anandita Mahika, Alejandro Gutierrez, Sienna Guo, Xiang Zhao, Ralph Marcucio, Nils Forkert, Benedikt Hallgrímsson. *Deep Learning for Automatic Analysis of Light-Sheet Microscopy Images of Mouse Embryos.* Poster. 8th Meeting of the European Society for Evolutionary Developmental Biology. May 2022. Napoli, Italy.
- Rebecca M. Green^{*}, **Lucas Lo Vercio**, Sienna Guo, Andreas Dauter, Marta Marchini, Xiang Xhao, Ralph S. Marcucio, Benedikt Hallgrímsson. *Mapping the relationship between proliferation and morphology in the developing mouse face*. Experimental Biology. April 2020. Virtual.
- Carolina Bruscantini^{+,*}, **Lucas D. Lo Vercio**, Pablo Rinaldi. *Correction of Digital Elevation Models based on Radar, using Land-sat Imagery and Machine Learning.* Lecture Presentation. XII Argentinian Congress of Agroinformatics (CAI 2020). 2020. La Plata, Argentina.
- Eugenia Moris^{+,*}, **Lucas D. Lo Vercio**, Ignacio Larrabide. *Automatic detection of morphological structures in Intravascular Ultrasound images with Convolutional Neural Network.* Lecture Presentation. Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery Congress. 2019. Rennes, France.
- **Lucas Lo Vercio***, José Ignacio Orlando, Mariana del Fresno, Ignacio Larrabide. *Assessment of image features for vessel wall segmentation in intravascular ultrasound images.* Poster and short presentation. Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery Congress. 2015. Barcelona, Spain.

INVITED TALKS

- May 2018. *Machine Learning for Image Processing*. Invited talk: 1st Workshop Red argentina de neuroimágenes y mapeo cerebral. Florencio Varela, Argentina.
- June 2017. Computer-aided diagnosis using ultrasound imaging. Invited talk: Post-secondary Education, Science and Technology. Coronel Vidal, Argentina.

Awards, Fellowships, & Grants _____

2015	Student Scholarship to attend to CARS 2015, International Society for Computer Aided	€1,000
	Surgery.	€1,000
2017-2018	Post-Doctoral Fellowship, CONICET	
2012-2017	Doctoral Fellowship, CONICET	
2007	2nd Place - Student project, Jornadas Argentinas de Informática.	

Scientific Community _____

Reviewer, Journals: Ultrasonics, Computers in Biology and Medicine, Medical Physics, BioMedical Engineering
OnLine, Methods in Ecology and Evolution, International Journal for Numerical Methods in Biomedical
Engineering, Physics in Medicine and Biology, Ultrasonic Imaging, Journal of Neural Engineering, GigaScience,
Medical Image Analysis.

2021-date Member, Red de Científicos Argentinos en Canadá

- 2017 Session Chair: Computer Vision, VI Congreso de Matemática Aplicada, Computacional e Industrial. Comodoro Rivadavia, Argentina
- 2016 Local organizing committee member. Student Poster Session Organizer., 12th International Symposium on Medical Information Processing and Analysis (SIPAIM 2016). Tandil, Argentina
- 2009 Local organizing committee member, XVIII Congreso sobre métodos numéricos y sus aplicaciones. Tandil, Argentina

R&D Projects_

A3SIS: Machine learning for detection and classification in satellite images. Ministry of Defense (Argentina). PIDDEF 12/16. 2017-2019. Director/Vice director.

HI-MED - Computational tools for image quantification, simulation and planning of treatments in medicine. MINCyT-ANPCyT (Argentina). PICT 2016-0116. 2017-2018. Personnel.

Imaging and simulation for diagnosis and treatment of vascular diseases. MINCyT-ANPCyT (Argentina). PICT 2014-1730. 2015-2017. Personnel.

SIMECO - Ultrasound simulator for medical training. PDTS-PCTI-158, Ministry of Science, Technology and Innovation (Argentina). 2014. Consultant - programmer.

Technical Knowledge _____

Medical Image Processing: Intravascular Ultrasound (IVUS), Common Carotid Artery Ultrasound (CCA US), Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT), Computed Tomography (CT), Optical Projection Tomography (OPT), micro-Computed Tomography (micro-CT), Light-Sheet Microscopy (LSFM).

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, Java; MATLAB; SQL.

Machine Learning: SVMs, Random Forests, CNNs, GANs.

Developer Tools: Microsoft Visual Studio; Eclipse IDE; MATLAB; IBM Rational Software Architect; Paraview, 3DSlicer, Py-Charm.

Teaching Experience _____

2023	MDSC 689.11 - Medical Imaging Applications, Guest lecturer. Topics: Image registration, Machine Learning.	UCalgary
2022	Workshop: Introduction to Image Processing using Open-Source Software, Instructor. Topics: Filtering. Segmentation. 3DSlicer, Paraview, ITK, Python.	UCalgary
2014, 2015, 2017	Medical Imaging workshop , Teaching Assistant. Topics: Filtering, segmentation, quantification and registration of medical images.	UNCPBA
2009-2018	Software Development Methodologies I, Teaching Assistant. Topics: UML, UP, Agile software development. IBM Professional Qualification "RT011 - Modeling of Object-Oriented Systems with Rational"	UNCPBA
2016-2018	Information Technologies for Organizations , Teaching Assistant. Topics: Fundamentals of organizations, Business requirements, software versioning, CMMI.	UNCPBA
2011-2019	Design of Compilers I , Teaching Assistant. Topics: Symbols tables, lexical and syntactic analysis, YACC, Assembly language.	UNCPBA
2011	Data Storage Structures , Teaching Assistant. Topics: Data modeling (Entity-Relationship Diagrams, Normal Forms, Business Requirements) and data structures in secondary storage (Hash maps, B and B+ trees).	UNCPBA

Mentoring	
2021 Co-Supervisor of Honours thesis for the Bachelor in Health Sciences , One (1) student	UCalgary

	•	9 ,
2020-2021	Co-Supervisor of Summer Studentships, Two (2) students	UCalgary
2017-2020	Supervisor of Final Projects for the degree in Systems Engineer, Four (4) students	UNCPBA
2017-2018	Supervisor of Research Student Fellowships, Two (2) students	UNCPBA

Departamental Services _____

2021	Judge, McCaig Institute Summer Student Symposium, University of Calgary, Canada
2019-2020,	Postdoctoral representative, McCaig Institute Trainee Committee, University of Calgary, Canada
2021-2022	Postuoctoral representative, McCaig institute Trainee Committee, Oniversity of Caigary, Canada
2015-2018	Member of various Teaching Assistant selection committees, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas, UNCPBA, Argentina
2015-2017	Member of various Final Project evaluation committees, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas, UNCPBA, Argentina

Languages _____

Spanish

NATIVE LANGUAGE

English

CELPIP (OCTOBER 2022)